<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://blog.catwizard.io/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://blog.catwizard.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-30T17:59:33+01:00</updated><id>http://blog.catwizard.io/</id><title type="html">Catwizard Blog</title><subtitle>A place to tell our stories.</subtitle><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name></author><entry><title type="html">Software Integrations and the sacredness of time</title><link href="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/11/08/integrations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Software Integrations and the sacredness of time" /><published>2018-11-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/11/08/integrations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/11/08/integrations.html">&lt;div id=&quot;entry-table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc-wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;toc-toggle&quot; class=&quot;no_toc&quot;&gt;
  Table of Contents &lt;i class=&quot;toc-toggle-icon fas fa-chevron-down&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#nota-para-la-proxima&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-nota-para-la-proxima&quot;&gt;NOTA PARA LA PROXIMA:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#systems-help-my-wife-needs-her-fix&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-systems-help-my-wife-needs-her-fix&quot;&gt;Systems help! My wife needs her fix!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-sacredness-of-time&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-sacredness-of-time&quot;&gt;The sacredness of time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#different-faces-of-system-integrations&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-different-faces-of-system-integrations&quot;&gt;Different faces of system integrations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#our-first-integrations-exp&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-our-first-integrations-exp&quot;&gt;Our first Integrations Exp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#market-facts-systems-integrations-an-increasing-focus-point-for-buisinesses&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-market-facts-systems-integrations-an-increasing-focus-point-for-buisinesses&quot;&gt;Market Facts: Systems Integrations, an increasing focus point for buisinesses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#amazon-raised-the-bar-for-b2b-and-b2c-not-sure-about-this-section-maybe-needs-to-go&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-amazon-raised-the-bar-for-b2b-and-b2c-not-sure-about-this-section-maybe-needs-to-go&quot;&gt;Amazon raised the bar, for B2B and B2C (NOT SURE ABOUT THIS SECTION, MAYBE NEEDS TO GO)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#this-is-not-only-for-enterprises-small-and-medium-business-need-a-strategy-not-sure-about-this-section-maybe-needs-to-go&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-this-is-not-only-for-enterprises-small-and-medium-business-need-a-strategy-not-sure-about-this-section-maybe-needs-to-go&quot;&gt;This is not only for enterprises, small and medium business need a strategy (NOT SURE ABOUT THIS SECTION, MAYBE NEEDS TO GO)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-do-pim-mdm-and-bi-have-in-common&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-do-pim-mdm-and-bi-have-in-common&quot;&gt;What do P.I.M, M.D.M and B.I have in common?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-summarized-checklist-for-software-integration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-a-summarized-checklist-for-software-integration&quot;&gt;A Summarized Checklist for Software integration&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-you-do-is-more-important-then-how-you-do-it&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-you-do-is-more-important-then-how-you-do-it&quot;&gt;What you do is more important then how you do it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#visual-overview-of-the-end-process&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-visual-overview-of-the-end-process&quot;&gt;Visual Overview Of the End Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1-modeling-data-identify-entities&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-1-modeling-data-identify-entities&quot;&gt;1. Modeling Data: Identify Entities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2-choosing-architcture-centralized-vs-virtualized&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-2-choosing-architcture-centralized-vs-virtualized&quot;&gt;2. Choosing Architcture: Centralized Vs Virtualized&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3-identify-source-systems&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-3-identify-source-systems&quot;&gt;3. Identify Source Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#4-matching-strategy&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-4-matching-strategy&quot;&gt;4. Matching Strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#5-master-records&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-5-master-records&quot;&gt;5. Master Records&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#6-survivorship-fields&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-6-survivorship-fields&quot;&gt;6. Survivorship fields&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-techonology-to-use-custom-made-vs-third-party-vendors&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-techonology-to-use-custom-made-vs-third-party-vendors&quot;&gt;What techonology to use. Custom Made vs Third Party Vendors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#custom-technology-stack&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-custom-technology-stack&quot;&gt;Custom Technology Stack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#get-returns-fast-using-agile-and-prototyping&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-get-returns-fast-using-agile-and-prototyping&quot;&gt;Get returns fast using Agile and prototyping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#loose-pieces&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-loose-pieces&quot;&gt;Loose pieces&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#customers-demand-content&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-customers-demand-content&quot;&gt;Customers Demand Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#grow-market-share-through-fast-and-relevant-marketing&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-grow-market-share-through-fast-and-relevant-marketing&quot;&gt;Grow Market Share through fast and relevant marketing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#donnation&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-donnation&quot;&gt;Donnation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nota-para-la-proxima&quot;&gt;NOTA PARA LA PROXIMA:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creo que debo quitar lo que no estoy convencido que puse en los titulos, dejar los pasos de design desicions cortos, pero una referencia con la explicacion de los mismos a otro post, Y dejar la parte de tech, donde hablo sobre que tech usar, y custom vs vendors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;systems-help-my-wife-needs-her-fix&quot;&gt;Systems help! My wife needs her fix!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I came out of the dentist office. She went for a check-in but they had to operate, she ended up druged, and desoriented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Make sure she takes this drug in the next hour or so, else the pain will bring her to tears once the sedative wears off, there is a pharmacy right in front of the building, but you know, lately patient have told me the drug is hard to find”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drug was a common one, but our political and in consequence economical situation was starting to be uncommon. We went to the pharmacy, no luck, then to the next one… same luck… none!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time was running out, and then she grabed me and told me… “Use the web page we developed for god’s sake!! It’s starting to hurt!!”… Riiiight, I had forgotten about that one…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-sacredness-of-time&quot;&gt;The sacredness of time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man is ill equiped to manage time, however, time is the most important resource in your life, and in your business. Traditionally, business theory teaches us that there are 3 types of resources: Capital, People and Time. Let’s break it down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Time is also a unique resource. Of the other major resources, money is actually quite plentiful.We long ago should have learned that it is the demand for capital, rather than the supply thereof, which sets the limit to economic growth and activity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Effective-Executive-Definitive-Harperbusiness-Essentials/dp/0060833459&quot;&gt;The Effective Executive&lt;/a&gt;
 by Peter F. Drucker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And regarding people, we can always hire people, even though good people are hard to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But Time! Time is unique!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for time, no matter how high the demand, the supply will not go up. There is no price for it, and it can’t be stored in any way. Yesterday time is gone and it will never come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, everything requires time, it is the true and only universal condition. All work takes time, uses time, requires time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… Yet most people take for granted this unique, irreplaceable, and necessary resource. Nothing else, perhaps, distinguishes effective executives as much as their tender loving care of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the best executives in the world go to great lenghts to learn how to save their time, so they can use whe it matter most, where it makes a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is a way to use systems to create pockets of time for everyone in the business. For the customer, employee, provider, manager, stakeholder, and for the most important person of all, for you…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the way? You might ask, well this one you heard before… Systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But I already have systems in the business” you might say… “in fact we have many. And man, what a complication it is! It’s overwhelming!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well yeah, but are they &lt;strong&gt;integrated&lt;/strong&gt; between them? are they &lt;strong&gt;team&lt;/strong&gt; players or individualists? Do they &lt;strong&gt;collaborate to create a better system&lt;/strong&gt; for everyone do they confuse? Do they help you to provide the service expected by today’s standards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design and succesful implementation of integrations create wealths of time. Just in time information converts into fast service, and less worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But! Just as a drug, systems can do wonders if prescribed correctly, and wreack havocks if applied incorrectly. Take your time to understand the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing these collaborations is not an easy task, and it’s becoming mandatory for survival, I hope this article saves you time, your must valuable resource, and points you into the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will give you a tip before we dive deeper, a big time saving secret: TEST BEFORE YOU IMPLEMENT. Yes, your or your provider, do some mockups, or prototypes. They can be done in Google Slides, Invision, or a piece of paper, and put users to the test. This will save you money and time big time. It can save years!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Every business is a software business”
said Watts S. Humphrey, the father of quality in software and CMMI 2 decades ago, and it’s repeated by The CEO of Microsoft, Satya Nadella today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Every company is a software company. You have to start thinking and operating like a digital company. It’s no longer just about procuring one solution and deploying one. It’s not about one simple software solution. It’s really you yourself thinking of your own future as a digital company.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;different-faces-of-system-integrations&quot;&gt;Different faces of system integrations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business Intellegence (B.I.),  Enterprise Resource Planning or ERP (Think SAP software), Product Information Management (P.I.M), Master Data Management (M.D.M), even Zappier, are all faces of the same beast, they all promise to gather data, centralize it, and turn it into useful informatino, and ready for you when you need it most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, before feeling overwhelm about the challange, know this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can reap the benefits of integrations, one step at the time. You do not need to invest in a 3 year project now, just 3 months, do a small integration, enjoy the returns of your investment, and afterwards put the next brick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slow but un-interrupted. This is a much faster way then it looks like, and it creates a habit, and habits my friend shape reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip&lt;/strong&gt;: Aim for effectiveness. What is the one question that if answered fater would solved many problems at once, for the most people in the compay? Identify and focus on that one, do not try to take on 10 inarticulated information problems. You won’t solve them, you will create a 7 head beast that will breath to your neck at all times, will waste money, team effort, and most important, waste tons of Time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining your current systems can achieve more then you can imagine, in most cases more then aquiring new systems. Don’t believe me? ask most legacy banks in the world in what language do they run their fundations… Does Kobol rings a bell? well it shouldn’t, Kobol is one old piece of technology, no longer teached, but a scary size of the financing systems of the world runs on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those tasks where is not the amount of hours spent what will give you returns, but the quality of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-first-integrations-exp&quot;&gt;Our first Integrations Exp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 8 years ago, we were asked to estimate, develop and implement a module to our in-house made web software, an online web catalog system (yes the on at the intro!), so it would integrate with the accounting systems of all the stores and provide one unified view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/integrations_1/farmaplus_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;farmaplus&quot; /&gt;
(List of physical stores, green menas available, yellow there are a few left, red means not available)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Farmaplus is a pharmacy, and the motivation behind the online system was to save customers time, by giving them price and availability information based on inventory rotation with a 10 to 15 minutes delay, providing them with better service vs the 24 hours delay of the competition back then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It saved time to customers, to employess, gave useful information to laboratories, helped managers and gave piece of mind to stake holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, and while the scarcity of medicines and other products increased, this channel transformed the buisiness making it the priority over the conventional printed catalog, became a sales focus point, helped a lot of people including myself to find their medicine, and was responsible for giving meaning and direction to our team and the evolution of that software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years after we internotialized we kept working on integrations, connecting nationals and internationals companies eith all kinds of systems: CRM’s such as saleforce, commercial websites, quoting systems, shopify implementations, accounting systems,  warehouses, health clubs, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;market-facts-systems-integrations-an-increasing-focus-point-for-buisinesses&quot;&gt;Market Facts: Systems Integrations, an increasing focus point for buisinesses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is our desicions, not our conditions, that shape our reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making the decision at the right time define our reality . . But for making a good enough decision, we need key information, not all information! Just the right one, at the right time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Where are you going bro?”, I asked my brother some years back as I watched him getting ready to paarrtyy!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“My company is throwing a party, it’s going to be sick man!”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Awesome! what are you guys celebrating?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“It appears that after 3 years and millions of dollars, our company finally integrated sytems from different departaments! Everyone is very excited!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah… brace yourself bro, it’s going to get geeky. Market and SKU geeky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, I did months of market research around product information and integration software. We had created a system over the years that solved many integrations issues. We decided to create a business plan for evaluation and se how far could we take it, thus I talked to a lot of software vendors, following the white rabbit into a deep rabit hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some facts I pulled out from the research that might hopefully prompt you to take some kind of action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- By 2015, 64% percent of adults in the USA buy online because the products presented there have more precise information than in stores. (Source: Forrester 2016: Product Information Management Solutions, Q4 2016). This strategy seems to work, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/topics/2477/online-shopping-behavior/&quot;&gt;statista.com&lt;/a&gt;, retail e-commerce sales worldwide are forecast to nearly double between 2016 and 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2- InRiver, one of the many integration software vendors, claims that they have an annual growth rate (CAGR) of %70. I did check other vendors data, and all of them have growned big time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3- 87% of data liders and analysts implemented or are planing to implement or expand on PIM (Software Integration for Products). Why? Managing spreadsheet and separated systems is not sustainable. To save time, minimize errors, increase time to market, and manage constantly changing requirements content for allies, digital business need automated checks (Source: Vendor Landscape: Product Information Management (PIM), Q3 2017)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4- In 2015, %67 of desicion makers related to infraestructure said that develop a complete strategy in the cloud was a high or critical priority. Additionally %56 projected an increase on investment in cloud services by the en of 2015. (Source: The Forrester WaveTM: Master Data Management, Q1 2016)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5- Experiences in the B2C world increase B2B purchases, almost 75% say that buying from a web page is more convenient than buying to sales representatives when they buy products or services for work. (Source: PIM Is A Cornerstone Of Your Digital Business Why Customer-Obsessed Firms Need Product Information Management January 18, 2017)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amazon-raised-the-bar-for-b2b-and-b2c-not-sure-about-this-section-maybe-needs-to-go&quot;&gt;Amazon raised the bar, for B2B and B2C (NOT SURE ABOUT THIS SECTION, MAYBE NEEDS TO GO)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello sir! Thank you for your quote request, we will give you an answer about your quote in a few weeks…” Yes, &lt;strong&gt;in a few weeks&lt;/strong&gt;, they have to make a few calls inside and outside the company to give the number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of service was ok a few years back, but todays users have a different standard, both consumers and B2B expect faster responses. To achieve this using organization is not enough, automation is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon raised the bar, Enterprises started to invest in this integration sytems 5 years ago, all users want the information &lt;strong&gt;now&lt;/strong&gt;, to make their desicion, they need the information, and they need accurate information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On-time information is simply more valuable then ever. It will define you as a service provider. A customer can make a desicion now to choose you if they have the information, and will choose the one who can give it to them sooner, even if you got better prices and other conditions, if the information is late your customer might have already decided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration between systems to provide unified views is a common problem that only traditionally enterprises were able to address: to be able to provide an unified view of information that is usually scattered across systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-is-not-only-for-enterprises-small-and-medium-business-need-a-strategy-not-sure-about-this-section-maybe-needs-to-go&quot;&gt;This is not only for enterprises, small and medium business need a strategy (NOT SURE ABOUT THIS SECTION, MAYBE NEEDS TO GO)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now days a new software model is already stablished, one that 10 years ago was unimaginable. Software as a Service (SaaS) is a model in which software is licensed on a subscription basis and is centrally hosted by another company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support, product updates, year licence, installations… all of this required a big budget to implement, now in your hands for $49,99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think gmail or any other email provider for business. You get an awesome and otherwise very expensive product and service for a monthly fee, and you don’t have to worry about updates, hardware, maintainance, etc… Some examples of what a company might choose:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freshbooks for accounting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salesforce as a CRM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shopify for web ecommerce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MailChimp for marketing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wordpress for the webpage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cisco Webex for video meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list grows and goes to different segments according to your industry. Gym Owner? Maybe you have something like VirtuaGym. Learning a language? maybe you are paying a monthly fee to memrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, as a small buisiness grows, and grows on top of different SaaS software, the typycal problem of integration arises. You’re users demand better service, better service means better information, and to do that you need to integrate it. You have offcourse some systems that are now SaaS and in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you have some systems that are traditionally inside your company. You already got that working, and the investment payed out a long time ago…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-pim-mdm-and-bi-have-in-common&quot;&gt;What do P.I.M, M.D.M and B.I have in common?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, they are all tools to centralize the data accross different systems and creating meaningfull views from them. Useful, time saving, smile givers, decision empowering, wealth builders, information in view format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MDM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Master Data Management&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Master Data is the consistent and uniform set of identifiers and extended attributes that describes the core entities of the enterprise including customers, prospects, citizens, supplier, sites, hierarchies and chart of accounts&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;PIM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Product Information Management&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Central set of product data can be used to feed information to media (Website, catalogs, ERP, feeds)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;BI&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Business Intelligence&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Delivers relative and reliable information at the right people, at the right time, using methods and programs to collect and structure data, and presents it in a meaningful and actionable way.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-summarized-checklist-for-software-integration&quot;&gt;A Summarized Checklist for Software integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design wise, and in my opinion, this are the key desicions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design and test a prototype/mockup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modeling Data: Identify Entities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choosing the Architecture: Centralized Vs Virtualized&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify Source Systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose The Matching Strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following is a general guide to systems integrations, and the techonology I would use to create a custom integration system. There are tons of technologies to accomplish this, some are general like an ERP system, some very specific for a domain, for example PIM integrates information around a product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are going to integrate information about hospital for example, then a different system specialized for hopsitals can be used or develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My intentions is to create a general solutions so most readers can understand the general process… at least how we have approached it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fuide is a modified version of a more techinical guide created by &lt;a href=&quot;https://es.slideshare.net/Dataversity/lessons-in-data-modeling-data-modeling-mdm&quot;&gt;Industry Expert Donna Burbank&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you Donna for helping us grow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-you-do-is-more-important-then-how-you-do-it&quot;&gt;What you do is more important then how you do it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[SHOW SIMPLE MAP OF BEGINING AND END]
The first step of the process is to have a clear view of the end result, and test it. Yes, test it even in the most simple way posible, this means putting a fake mockup infront of your user and see if it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create some simple mockups and screens with the ideas. Invision is a wonderful tool for this, but microsoft presentation would do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create something that is real enough to have the feel of the interaction of the main tasks, and no, you don’t need a designer for this, it’s a fake, like movie setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We like to use Google’s Venture Spring Process [ADD LINK] because is a proven profesional process, but sometimes you only need to do some mockups on a white board, iterate over that and that will create a mockup good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the screen views in place and tested a little, you should have a view of the main screens of your system integration. You are now ready to start modeling your data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visual-overview-of-the-end-process&quot;&gt;Visual Overview Of the End Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a simplified view of integrated systems life cycle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frequently load data from &lt;strong&gt;sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Constantly match sources data to &lt;strong&gt;master data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show information in &lt;strong&gt;end users views&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2 IMAGES, PROCESS AND END VIEWS]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sources&lt;/strong&gt; are anywhere the data is store. They can be systems, databases, spreadsheets, datawharehouses, etc…
&lt;strong&gt;master data&lt;/strong&gt; are identifier that tie id’s from other systems togethers, such as product SKU, customer id, invoice numbers. Also called Master Record
&lt;strong&gt;end users views&lt;/strong&gt; are the views you created in the previews steps, the mockups. This is what the user interacts with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we know what we want, we need to model the data to accomplish the integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-modeling-data-identify-entities&quot;&gt;1. Modeling Data: Identify Entities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to identify the entities that you need to integrate, so you can accomplish the end views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of entities as nouns in the system, some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer, SalesPerson (who?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Product, Service (what?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quote, Order (why?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location (where?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invoice (How?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will probably need mixed views from every entity, after that, we can go to the next step and choose the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-choosing-architcture-centralized-vs-virtualized&quot;&gt;2. Choosing Architcture: Centralized Vs Virtualized&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Slide of Choosing MDM Model: Centralized Vs Virtualized]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should we create data structures to save temporaly information from the systems? Or should we reuse the information directly from the sources and create a virtual layer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, we have always used the Centralized approach. Mostly because almost always we need some field to make sense of the data, for example to recomend products between them, to save a reference of a document produced by the centrilized system, for historical purposes (e.g. generated quote id), are a few examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-identify-source-systems&quot;&gt;3. Identify Source Systems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we need to identify the sources, CRM, In-Store sales, warehouses, supply chain, finance, marketing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central model will create a super set of data, where websites, mobile apps, and other applications can reference the “Golden Record”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, this central aplication will provide an API, a set of commands to comunicate directly with the centralized data once, as opposed to communicat to the original sources one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-matching-strategy&quot;&gt;4. Matching Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a fundamental part of your integration. If your matching strategy is not realistic, then all of your investment will be lost!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matching is the process of crossing the records of different systems and tying them into the one record, and identified as equivalent. So if it’s left half way, the system won’t be useful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, we select an automatic matching rule, and then we let humans check review them and fix them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1. Unique fields matching rules&lt;/strong&gt;
Rules to be added so the system can check and automatically match records from both systems. For example email or social security number for people, SKU’s for products, or combinations of fields such as (last name + date of birth)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can add a list of rules for the system to check, and if match is found then create an automatic match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2. Fuzzy Matching&lt;/strong&gt;
For recommending matching strings such as names, product names and addresses where human error or different entry standards between systems can cause slight variations in similar values eg: “Joe Smith” vs “J Smith”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Match scores are created between each fuzzy logic match, for example, using this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/xdrop/fuzzywuzzy&quot;&gt;Java library&lt;/a&gt;, it would be somehitng like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FuzzySearch.ratio(&quot;mysmilarstring&quot;,&quot;myawfullysimilarstirng&quot;)= 72&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FuzzySearch.ratio(&quot;mysmilarstring&quot;,&quot;mysimilarstring&quot;) = 97&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the rule could be &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;if ratio &amp;gt; 85&lt;/code&gt; then do a match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3. Matching Approval: Key Role&lt;/strong&gt;
Ideally you would have 2 kind of review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- By someone internally
2- By end users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both should have a way to comunicate a mismatch if found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 4. Remember to allow manual matching&lt;/strong&gt;
Finally, your system should be able to allow manual matching, to address exceptional cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-master-records&quot;&gt;5. Master Records&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a matching has been applied to the records, an internal reference table is maintained with the unique ids of the matching entities of the systems and a Master ID that holds the reference of both systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data administrator will have the ability review and un-match between systems if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-survivorship-fields&quot;&gt;6. Survivorship fields&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, this concept refers to defining the attributes or fields to be used from each system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-techonology-to-use-custom-made-vs-third-party-vendors&quot;&gt;What techonology to use. Custom Made vs Third Party Vendors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not have a straight answer for this, I can only give my opinion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vendors are usually interested in selling their software and what you need, which is the guidance and of what to integrate, most commercial offers from the companies that I talked to for P.I.M software do not include the integration itself, they redirect you to integrators that they know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they will tell you this clearly at the very end of the selling process. At first is all “yes, yes, do not worry”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several vendors out there, but last time I checked, very few where key on hand solutions, and the ones that do serve the Enterprise sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our experience this is our proposed Techonology Stack and Development Methodology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;custom-technology-stack&quot;&gt;Custom Technology Stack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend development with Jhipster. I’m developing software since before I started Engineering. After years of consultancy and tons of custom development, I find this platform incredible robust and productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of it like a magic wepon, you need enough level to use it, but when used correctly it generates enterprise quality for a fraction of the costs. You can integrate techonologies that usually would take weeks to integrate. Here are some of the features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ready to use API for web and mobile apps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Powerfull cross attributes database search (Elastic search)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Production ready code (optimized and tested)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generation of Quality Assurance Tests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sql, and no Sql databases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microservices support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Auto generated interactive documentation (swagger)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main benefit is a combination of relaibility, quality, speed and flexability. In short, saving time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies that use it? From Adobe, to Decathlon, USA Defense department, many banks like, etc….(see jhipster webpage)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Creation is to combine ingridients in the right amount of propotions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-returns-fast-using-agile-and-prototyping&quot;&gt;Get returns fast using Agile and prototyping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;loose-pieces&quot;&gt;Loose pieces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;customers-demand-content&quot;&gt;Customers Demand Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason customers expect rich, relevant, continually updated content to help them through each step of the customer journey, regardless of purchase touchpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grow-market-share-through-fast-and-relevant-marketing&quot;&gt;Grow Market Share through fast and relevant marketing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been proven long ago that the way to grow your market share is with great customer experiences. Systems integrations allows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To grow market share with great customer
experiences, digital businesses must assess
their merchandising and product management
benchmarks and modernize their product
information management processes and
capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find hidden opportunities in time to take action, correct unhealthy habbits, provide better service, be able to adapt to changes in an agile way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;donnation&quot;&gt;Donnation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you liked this article and would want to see more, please&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name><email>ernesto@catwizard.io</email></author><category term="PIM / MDM" /><category term="Software Integration" /><category term="software" /><summary type="html">Software Integrations</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LingoStand Post 1</title><link href="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/11/07/lingostand_1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LingoStand Post 1" /><published>2018-11-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/11/07/lingostand_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/11/07/lingostand_1.html">&lt;p&gt;LingoStand mission is to help users attain communication level in a new language as quickly as posible, and later to accelerate their current level specializing in a particular topic or area of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first course helps the user to learn the meaning and usage of the most used words in a language on its real context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the millions of words on a language, you only need to understand a small set to be able to communicate and learn how to use them in real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native speakers with a low education level do not know a big set of words. But they only need a small group of words to be able to communicate. If you go surfing in Venezuela, you need only to speak with native fishermen, and you can communicate using a small word set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been proven multiple times that to learn faster, is better for you to use content that you are really interested in, because you will come back to practice with more often, with real intention and interest. For this reason, we are constantly updating our library with new trending articles as well as classic books and stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are constantly re-inventing our interface and technology around these goals.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name><email>ernesto@catwizard.io</email></author><category term="learn language" /><category term="lingostand" /><category term="software" /><summary type="html">Why Lingostand</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The meaning of life for a software professional</title><link href="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/10/22/meaning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The meaning of life for a software professional" /><published>2018-10-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/10/22/meaning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/10/22/meaning.html">&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about the meaning of life, about how I’m working towards finding it through my work and to share my journey. Hopefully, it helps someone in some unforeseen way, worst case it helps me explore myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I have run a small Software Consulting Development company for years, but we are in transition to becoming an Independent Software development company or studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m of course much more complex than a software developer tag, consultant, programmer, etc… just like you are much more complex than your professional tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also a book addict, specially self-help book addict, especially to practical books…  I really like testable information. Read, analyze, test, do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I like about software and self-help books is how both can change the current course of your life. For me, the code in both sources contains real magic, assuming they are one of the good ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can read a book, and if it’s the right book at the right time it can transform my life forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To accomplish this, I need to take the time to read it slowly, allowing the information to take a hold a little each day in me, like a plant you water and it slowly starts to grow, changing my thoughts, my believes, my habits and finally my circumstances. They can be a transformative experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-quiting-to-healing-back-backpain-to-finding-meaning&quot;&gt;From quiting, to healing back backpain, to finding meaning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take Allen Carr’s Easy Way to Stop Smoking for example, man talk about a good investment!! I smoked a lot since I was 15 years old up to 36, and the few attempts I had made of quitting were pathetic. A few months and then I was back. After reading that book a bit each day, I developed a complete rejection for a cigarette. 2 years have passed and I can’t stand the smell of it, I respond to it like a non-smoker would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is one thing to fight a bad habit with willpower “one day at the time”, and another one entirely to re-write your programming to reject it not needing willpower at all. If you reprogarm yourself correctly, you just can’t stand the smell, no will power needed. What did the book say? What was the revolutionary message? Smoking is bad for you health, your economy, your self confidence… etc… I had offcourse heard the messages before, but it was written in such a way that if you consumed about 30 minutes each day of the book, by the end of it I really belived the message, it was part of my unconscious. At some point in the reading and real life observation cycle something clicked, I made a desicion, and from that instant I felt a rejection for cigarettes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another practical example is John Sarno’s Healing Back Pain book. I had a recurrent and very painful back spasms since 2012 until May 2017. Every 2 or 3 months my back got stiff, and every move in any direction was a world of pain. If I layed out and took anti-inflammatory medicine, in the course of a week I would be able to move again and pretend that nothing happened and I was ok. The first time I got it I was doing longboarding in Caracas and suddenly PAF… had to sit on the sidewalk and walk back home moving like a robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not want to go to the doctors, I was afraid they would give the pain a name and made the problem permanent. I’ve lost many outdoors activities buddies due to back pain diagnosis. Doctors do the best they can generally, but I learned through experience that an error in the diagnosis can condition oneself to always being sick, and even create an issue where there was none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the book in May 2017 after a very shameful episode at the CrossFit box, again a few pages each day, and well, no more episodes until now (November 2018). Again, abut 30 minutes a day, my thoughs started to change, the pain started to change slowly, until one day I made a life desicion and started to act accordingly and the pain was gone (turns out having internal conflicts causes all kinds of physicall pains).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;software-and-search-for-meaning&quot;&gt;Software and Search for Meaning.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on and on about all these books, and how they are continually shaping my life, but let’s focus on the main subject of this message: Meaning of Life. And for that, I’ll reference a book that contains something very special: Viktor Frankl’s Man’s Search for Meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said I favor tested practical content above theorists, and this one is tested in one of the most extreme environments ever produced in the history of mankind… Hitler’s concentration camps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that the author (who was one of the prisoners) illustrated in crude hardcore HD that physically strong people had far less chance of survival than educated unathletic people who were able to give their life meaning baffled me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of how people, when lost meaning entered a recognizable state that inevitably leads to death, made me wonder for days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one of the most incredible lessons was, that the meaning in your life is something you have to give to yourself. You have to make it up, make your own story, or borrow someone else’s and adjust it, do what you need to do to fabricate your reason to be in the world and then believe it, really believe it. And if you do, you will have a clear goal, and lot’s of energy to accomplish it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will find solutions to problems, and grow stronger as your solve them. One thing I got from Victor Frankling is that those who had meaning not only survived the concentration camps, but they were able to have a full life afterwards. They did not turn to the dark side, but were able to have a good life themselves and contribute making the world better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makes sense, I though, if you think about it. We are constantly making up stories to ourselves. Think about history’s highlighted characters, those that seem to have a driving force beyond human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example Magallanes and his crew, these guys actually did go around the world for the first time in history with equipments that shouldn’t have worked! First to America crossing the Atlantic, then discovered el canal de Magallanes mainly through believing that it existed without any proove, and then went and crossed the Pacific which was 3 times the lenght!! Compare them with todays astronauts that can pre plan the course… not taking anything out of our astronauts, I find them incredible, but they do have a bunch of thing estimated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-create-our-meaning-no-one-can-do-it-for-us&quot;&gt;We create our meaning, no one can do it for us.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not even important how big or important to others is this meaning, it only matters how big or important it is for you. Your world is what it’s really important. Viktor Frankl talked about people who’s meaning was taking care of their son, sharing time with his partner, or helping a friend that was in the camp. Others like Viktor were able to create other kinds of meaning, as a neurologist and psychiatrist, he saw himself comunicating the message of healing through meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, it is our job to find reasons to be excited about what we are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, one note based on expirience: This thing works much better if the meaning is a responsible one. I used to think that responsability was the opposite of freedom, but what I realized with this book is that freedom is a wide concept that has 2 sides of an spectrum, in one side is selfishness and in the other responsability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(ShowImage?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The responsability side is the one you can use as an element to create your meaning, the side that let’s you collaborate with what you have to give, transform your expiriences and your skills and put it at service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;consecuences-of-no-meaning&quot;&gt;Consecuences of no Meaning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viktor exemplifies how once meaning is lost, the persue of immediate pleasure takes over. In concentration camps, it was a clear sign that someone gave up, and his time on this earth was a matter of hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…a behavior pattern crystallized to which they referred as “give-up-itis.” In the concentration camps, this behavior was paralleled by those who one morning, at five, refused to get up and go to work and instead stayed in the hut, on the straw wet with urine and feces. Nothing—neither warnings nor threats—could induce them to change their minds. And then something typical occurred: they took out a cigarette from deep down in a pocket where they had hidden it and started smoking. At that moment we knew that for the next forty-eight hours or so we would watch them dying. Meaning orientation had subsided, and consequently the seeking of immediate pleasure had taken over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why, his conclusion, one he was able to test and put into practice during the war and for years after, is that meaning is our must important drive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Life is not primarily a quest for pleasure, as Freud believed, or a quest for power, as Alfred Adler taught, but a quest for meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmmm, so what about the reward system that is so used now? You know, the incentive system that the best employers put a lot of effort into implementing, the psychological game that must be part of a good negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That reward system embeded in games, your instagram likes, the system to be hacked in your new diet, to contrarest the pleasure of sugar, and the pain of tasteless brocoli… Well this is what the extreme experiment reveals about it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…man’s main concern is not to gain pleasure or to avoid pain but rather to see a meaning in his life. That is why man is even ready to suffer, on the condition, to be sure, that his suffering has a meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important note!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But let me make it perfectly clear that in no way is suffering necessary to find meaning. I only insist that meaning is possible even in spite of suffering—provided, certainly, that the suffering is unavoidable. If it were avoidable, however, the meaningful thing to do would be to remove its cause, be it psychological biological or political. To suffer unnecessarily is masochistic rather than heroic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– REVISE HASTA AQUI&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– AGREGAR LA PARTE DE EMYTH QUE HABLA DEL MEANING DEL TRABAJO PARA LAS PERSONAS: CHAPTER 16&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“He said, ‘The work we do is a reflection of who we are. If we’re sloppy at it, it’s because we’re sloppy inside. If we’re late at it, it’s because we’re late inside. If we’re bored by it, it’s because we’re bored inside, with ourselves, not with the work. The most menial work can be a piece of art when done by an artist. So the job here is not outside of ourselves, but inside of ourselves. How we do our work becomes a mirror of how we are inside.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Manager continued, as if the owner were talking through him. “Work is passive without you. It can’t do anything. Work is only an idea before a person does it. But the moment a person does it, the impact of the work on the world becomes a reflection of that idea—the idea behind the work—as well as the person doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In the process, the work you do becomes you. And you become the force that breathes life into the idea behind the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You become the creator of the impact on the world of the work you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There is no such thing as undesirable work,” he continued. “There are only people who see certain kinds of work as undesirable. People who use every excuse in the world to justify why they have to do work they hate to do. People who look upon their work as a punishment for who they are and where they stand in the world, rather than as an opportunity to see themselves as they really are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…  the business is a place where everything we know how to do is tested by what we don’t know how to do, and that the conflict between the two is what creates growth, what creates meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… That a business is like a martial arts practice hall, a dojo, a place you go to practice being the best you can be. But the true combat in a dojo is not between one person and another as most people believe it to be. The true combat in a martial arts practice hall is between the people within ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-buisiness-owner-to-consultant-to-product-developer&quot;&gt;From buisiness owner, to consultant, to product developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, since I was a child, I wanted my own buisiness. As soon as I graduated, I took the first opportunity at it. Now, being a buisiness owner of a buisiness that works, is one of the hardest challanges I have ever faced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What attracted me about it? In short, the freedom it supposed to give me. But the freedom has to be earned, and working hard in the wrong direction is probably the surest way of failing, and failing means being a slave of your buisiness, of your clients, of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The purpose of going into business is to expand beyond your existing horizons. So you can invent something that satisfies a need in the marketplace that has never been satisfied before. So you can live an expanded, stimulating new life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Because, the moment you chose to start a small business, Sarah, you unwittingly chose to play a significantly larger game than any game you had ever played before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For when the dream is gone, the only thing left is work.
The tyranny of routine.
The day-to-day grind of purposeless activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after going through all that I was like…. ok, how can I contribute? How can I find meaning? They say that questions will focus your attention into finding answers… Because finding meaning is something I definelty want in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is meaning? I would say, simply, something to live for, something to work for. A reason. For me it’s the story we make up ourself of &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; we are doing &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; we are doing. This &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; must be compelling enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a software professional I have felt a little of this in the past, I hope you have too. For example, in Venezuela we proposed and implemented an online system for some pharmacies so people could find medications. It updated inventory information from every branch of a city for each of their 7,500 product catalog. Back when we implemented it about 8 years ago, medical shortage was a big thing in Venezuela, and it’s worst each day. Now it’s a tragedy, just check it out for youself: [http://www.farmaplus.com.ve/#!/products].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That project made little profit, but back then it helped a lot of people, and some years afterwards when we ourselves needed the service urgently we were very happy to have built it. From all the projects we developed back then, that one I always remember with particular satisfaction, like we contributed. It is still used a lot daily by thousands of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;contrasting-this-with-other-more-profitable-projects&quot;&gt;Contrasting this with other more profitable projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have built other systems and work for different companies after that. We had an ecommerce project for women handbags in which users could pick a color and color it’s parts. Or another one where we helped cosmetic bottles and accesories distributors located in Miami, New Jersy and California to pick and quote cases of thousands of product using integrations to the wharehouses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both project where very interesting to make, however the feeling is not the same, knowing that what you made is helping people who really need it just give another meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what to do in these cases? A B2B distributor for example? Well we focused our meaning on how this features could make the employees lives of the people who worked in Businesses better, their employees, people we interacted with, people that worked with us in the projects. Once we focused our meaning on serving them then it was a fullfilling experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-do-infintly-more-important-than-how-you-do-it&quot;&gt;What you do infintly more important than how you do it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so this sentence I got from Tim Ferris and adopted it as a believe. We in the tech industry sometimes get so caught up on the perfect framework, the best methodology, the best language… Then we try to align our meaning to using this tools, and sometimes we can, but some times we force it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Industry teachs us that success is more about going viral, or having a good paying job, or nailing it as consultant with a high rate per hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We as human need this too, we need to have the need of certainty fulfilled, that we are going to be able to pay our bills, help our families, eat, have a roof, etc… Beleive me as a traveling inmigrant that can’t return to his country because it’s in a very bad shape, I know how important this is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But once you have a minimum certainty, meaning goes a long way, or as authous such as Viktor have demostrated, meaning will give you beyon human strenght&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns the main question that one would ask if you could go back in time and talk to these guys is Why? Why did you do all that? What motivated you? Well… each of them had different why’s different meanings. The stronger the meaning the more challanges were able to overcome. The stories of these guys makes the pirates of the caribean look boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was it will power? No, will power is very limited. Unconsciuos is incredible powerful. And it al comes to the meaning, to the why, and we can give ourself this meaning by fabricating our own story. Isn’t that amazingly? I think it’s more incredible then most scifi or fantasy stories. And it’s real, and we all have it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not even important how big or important to others is this meaning, it only matters how big or important it is for you. Your world is what it’s really important. Viktor Frankl talked about people who’s meaning was taking care of their son, sharing time with his partner, or helping a friend that was in the camp. Others like Viktor were able to create more meaning, as a neurologist and psychiatrist, he saw himself comunicating the message of healing through meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us are so confused because of years of publicity, social standards and other kind of influence, and also so out of touch with our own imagination that it’s very hard to make up this story, to make up this meaning for ourselves. Humans by nature will go by the easiests path: buy someone else’s fictional story. But many times the easiests path is fake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone else’s story is incomplete, it lacks definition, so we start borrowing pieces of other people stories, which conflict with each other, and create huge conflicts in ourselves, leaving our own story and sense of meaning empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some elements that make the sotry more compelling. One is making a responsible story. Being responsible is being free and caring at the same time, as opposed to free and selfish for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To build a meaning for yourself, strong enough to endure, it must be about contributing, and while building this meaning the self centereness will slowly go away, allowing a rich life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does a selfcentered software profesional fabricates a story full with meaning? how might he use his acquired skill to contribute? Well this is my journey, this is the story we are living, this is how we are turning the direction of our boat.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name><email>ernesto@catwizard.io</email></author><category term="story" /><category term="meaning of life" /><category term="lingostand" /><category term="software" /><summary type="html">My search toward growing and contribution &quot;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A thank you letter to the JHipster Team</title><link href="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/06/09/jhipster-thanks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A thank you letter to the JHipster Team" /><published>2018-06-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/06/09/jhipster-thanks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/06/09/jhipster-thanks.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you letter to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/juliendubois&quot;&gt;Julien Dubois&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/java_hipster&quot;&gt;JHipster Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Ernesto Buttó, I’m Co-Funder with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/laslorma&quot;&gt;Cindy Marin&lt;/a&gt; of a small software company (currently 3 people) called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catwizard.io&quot;&gt;catwizard.io&lt;/a&gt;. Cindy recently did a &lt;a href=&quot;http://catwizard.io/workshop.html&quot;&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; in Women Tech Makers Barcelona 2018 about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jhipster.tech/&quot;&gt;JHipster&lt;/a&gt;, and I wanted to say a few words about how JHipster has impacted our lives and the people around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comes as a way of thanking the JHipster team for making this platform. I figured that the best way we could do it was telling our story of JHipster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been working together for 11 years now. Cindy and I are both originally from Venezuela. We started a software company there that now days is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catwizard.io&quot;&gt;catwizard.io&lt;/a&gt;  (originally Bambu Soluciones). After getting our degrees in Computer Engineering, we started our professional path as software developers while also starting a company. Being programmers and entrepreneurs. During those early days, we were many, not just Cindy and I. We met our first partner, he had the idea of a building an online product catalog solution for a specific industry and a Content Management System to go with it. He sold us that he could sell it and he would become a supporter and mentor for the startup years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend recomended Spring as the backend, we figured Adobe Flex is the future in the front end… We, young and enthusiastic as we were for anything that sounded fancy and productive, followed. So we coded, we build, we sold. It worked! Kinda…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-about-code-business-and-market&quot;&gt;Learning about Code, Business and Market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was all growing slowly but surely as we became incrementally better in the technical and business front. We were learning how to be a company rather than a team, how to be profitable, how to manage money and time, while at the same learning how to write better code, how to manage ourselves as programmers. We learned to hire and to teach, we gave and took, and in the process, we met the third team member that has been working with us since then Fatima Pestana, data engineer with a taste for CSS and helping customers to achieve their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was like setting up the foundations of a house, sure it was slow, but whatever we were building, it was growing steady and strong. Then Venezuela happened. Economy and personal security levels went in a steep decline. Shortages of basic stuff began (toilet paper, eggs, legumes, milk, etc…) while crime rates went dramatically up. Saddened, we started to think about leaving. What future could we have in these circumstances? Then again: how do you leave behind all that you’ve built for years? How do you leave all your promises to your customers and to yourself? How do you just get on a plane, and… start from scratch? A small decision. To get through a door, to get on a car, to give a final hug, and your habits and definitions and reminders of who you are, in an instant, puff…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our company, however… We did not want stop working together. Our company. It grew into us. It was our dream. It was our vision. It was working, it was giving back. We just couldn’t. And at least about that, of all things, we were able to do something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To run it remotely”, we figured. So we did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, easier being said than done, amirite? Our business, our sole business at the moment was this: a set of modules and services that we sold to companies. Our sales strategy was based on trust that we had built, relying on existing customers that wanted new modules, and a support and service-oriented approach that contributed to our reputation spreading mostly by word of mouth. We basically ran most of the time in operations, while prospects and customers called and visited us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Venezuela kept happening. As the country tumbled, many of our customers were forced to close doors, or to stay operating at minimums depending on the industry, size, strategic view of the owners, with a heavy dose of unrelenting optimism, and faith. Lot’s of faith that it will all turn out for the best. Eventually…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what could we do? We can work remotely, ok, but most (not all) of our clients were closing shop, and nobody outside of Venezuela knew us. We figured that we could work on custom developments and consulting, primarily to costumers in the USA that we already had bonds with. Strengthen our relationships, you know. Improve our delivery times and features compliance, become competitive, while not forgetting about those in Venezuela that still relied upon us and somehow managed to stay afloat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;digital-nomads-vs-giving-up&quot;&gt;Digital Nomads vs Giving Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After living on the road for a few months, while being a consulting company and traveling to several countries (living the remote life, hooray!), including Colombia, Peru, Chile, Sicily, we decided to settle ourselves for a while in warm, sunny Spain, in a small city close to Barcelona called Girona. It was working great! We had challenges but we had freedom, we had stress but also relief. Responsibilities but also a taste of peace of mind, and less loud worries about politics or tragically, toilet paper (and I do mean less loud …family and friends are still there). We had left our home, but we were finally feeling like were building a new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost immediately after taking our first breath in our first Spanish flat, we were thrown into a very stressful situation. We accepted a project that was going to affect a core process of our main customers in the USA while a new opportunity involving a mobile app connecting via Bluetooth to an electric skateboard arose (stoked!).  We had very little time, and a very limited budget to handle it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our client’s business software touched many areas. It required security and reliability to handle everyday operations, it integrated SalesForce to their products marketing information system and to their accounting systems. We loved the project, but the resources and time frames were very short for such a software to be built from sratch. I could feel the risk of finishing the project and beraly being able to pay our bills, and in any other circumstances, we probably would not have agreed to do it, but by this time we have no other source of income and zero contacts in Spain. Nobody knew us, and we didn’t know how to market ourselves here. And on the other side there were the skateboard guys. New client, young guys with a revolutionary product at hand, with lots of promise and potential and interesting technologies… No much money upfront but if the project launched and worked then it would also make sense in the buisiness side… And it seemed so much fun!  We just couldn’t say no to that. What if this became the floating skateboard we are all waiting for? Our future selves would’ve never forgiven us. But no time, no money. What can we do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enter-jhipster&quot;&gt;Enter JHipster&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, 2 days after agreeing to the project with our USA client we were feeling like we were already falling behind. Very anxious and all that. We remembered that we had tried JHipster some years back, while fooling around on the Internet. I went and looked at it again and was amazed on everything the team had built around the generator. The JDL language, the ease of use of the development workflow, the generated security, the roles! The user’s administration, swagger integration, the monitors, the logging, the profiles, java testing, frontend testing, the sonar integration, performance tests, integration tests… I mean… all the options, man! Once I got a hold of the workflow using GitHub and all the tools JHipster provided I felt like Mickey in the Fantasia movie, the Wizard Mickey discovering that he has this magic, that he he owns it, and that he can create universes and life! We were suddenly able to learn and apply a lot of technologies and concepts that we simply could not afford in the past. There was a way of updating the entities fields and relationships, exporting the model. The production profile is so well packaged, the cache options, the database options, do you need realtime with websockets ? ultra fast Elasticsearch engine ? internationalization ? got it choose the languages… we included ng-prime and solved specific user interface requirements (Now days there is a module for that in the marketplace), and the Angular2 was almost out of Beta (They support Angular 5 now and React). I mean I was so excited of all the tech behind it and at all it could do for our customers, all it could do for us! Well… Fast forward some months and we are now delivering the project built in JHipster, approved for production (replacing a very old legacy lotus notes workflow, allowing collaboration between the users, monitoring, delivering branded PDF’s, creating tasks on the CRM etc…) and with a very happy client. We delivered on time and turned a profit thanks to the hours we saved. Even more, some other module, one that was approved after all of this and wasn’t even part of the original scope of the project, we were able to include it before hand. We had anticipated and we delivered! We were skipping through time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jhip1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jhipster Generator Example Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to that we were able to pay for the migration costs, find a better place to live, get our legal papers in order. That first breath of our new flat came again, and this time we managed to fully enjoy it. Ecstatic relief. Good news appeared: our client in the USA told us that their solution was used steadily in daily operations. We became able to help our partner in Venezuela (Fatima Pestana) dealing with the, by now, devastating economic crisis. We were helping family and friends leave the country. Thanks to JHipster we became again to not only be sustainable as a company but also to able to give back. To connect with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy came up with the idea of a JHipster workshop for the Women Tech Makers in Barcelona. It would not only show the many technical benefits of JHipster but it could also be purposed as a tool for empowerment. It turned out to be (at the time of this writing) the most viewed video of all the talks (&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/SoxR30Kkwj4&quot;&gt;you can check it out here&lt;/a&gt;). That same workshop inspired me to help in the next Software Craft Barcelona 2018 event and help Cindy to boost a GDG initiative at Girona. Spreading the word, be it via a workshop, or a long article in a small blog seems like the least we could do to say thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of generated update entity view&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jhip2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Example of generated update entity view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jhipster-boosts-learning&quot;&gt;JHipster boosts learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn you shall want and to learn you shall do! There’s so much to learn from JHipster. I mean… Let’s start with the code. The quality of the generated code (AAA in sonarqube currently!) is the result of well-thought concepts and solutions aimed at a very specific set of problems. What JHipster does, it does it well. Considering how easy it is to get confused in this world about best practices, best methodology, best strategies, best this, best that… There is a huge benefit of seeing those best bests in a tangible product, functioning in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small example in the Spring part: the service layer… Should I build a service layer for every endpoint, or can I get away with calling the repository directly? How should we deal with that kind of thing…? Ok, how does JHipster generates all those abstraction layers and why? Now, as responsible programmers, we go and read the documentation, test it with some cases, and very quickly arrive at our own conclusions. Because behind the tools there are philosophies and concepts that support the results, and because you provide several options regarding a particular practice, we can compare, we can experiment and tinker, we can be playful! (and everybody knows the importance of play)… Oh! yes let’s use service class in this case, interface in that case, but mostly let’s just call the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example swagger integration, out of the box JSON API interactive interface sandbox!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jhip3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jhipster Generator Example Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can recommend 100% JHipster to anyone who is on the path of learning about Java + Angular/React/Ionic , or about architectures, or about microservices, or about Spring security, or about DevOps (because the profiles, CI tools, deployment and docker stuff is awesome!), or about data modeling, or comparing paradigms like NoSQL vs SQL, or about multilanguage architecture, etc…If you’re reading this and are still not sure, I say: Yes, go through books and online courses and MOOCs and whatnot, but—as it is with anything worthy in this life—, I encourage you to get your hands dirty, as anything worthy in this life requires… Now, if you decided that yes, that you do want to get to the depths of some tech, to see it as it is and understand what it does, how it does it and what it really has to offer, not necessarily become an expert but really knowledgeable… I mean, if you really want to get your hands dirty, why not do it with some really really good mud? This is the algorithm: create a simple project with JHipster, see what it does, add a technology you would like to understand, see what it does now, repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I was learning and implementing docker, and we have a real use case of a company that has two monolith applications that work together communicating through their JSON API’s. I wasn’t sure if this was right, or common or if there are ways of packaging them. Came again JHipster. In the Docker section of the documentation I found this gem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If your architecture is composed of several JHipster applications, you can use &amp;gt; the specific docker-compose sub-generator, which will generate a global Docker &amp;gt; Compose configuration for all selected applications…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ooohh!! So it’s ok! It’s OK. They don’t have to be microservices to connect. And look at the docker-compose files! Certainly, we can start from here…!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jhipster-changed-the-game-for-us&quot;&gt;JHipster changed the game for us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this point, you must know that every technology in JHipster has a reason to be. It is useful by itself, yes, but it can be even more if combined with another one. To successfully implement these combinations (JWT Spring security + Angular for example, or ElasticSearch… or Social, etc..) by yourself is not trivial. Lot’s of trial and error, lot’s of mistakes, maybe even some expensive ones If you want to learn about it you need a lot of time, and budgets of SMBs project won’t cover for these researchers. JHipster provides a way. A low-cost way of learning not how to be a developer but how to be a good one. Not only using Spring in blind-following-the-blind fashion like when we were starting in Venezuela, but using it well; and that along Elasticsearch, and Docker, and Swagger and a myriad of other outstanding packages…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of generated monitor screen&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jhip4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jhipster Generator Monitor Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, JHipster was a fundamental solution during a very hard time of our lives, and it is now a fundamental part of our learning, our processes as developers and our processes as service providers. What else can I say but thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name><email>ernesto@catwizard.io</email></author><category term="story" /><summary type="html">How this amazing opensource project impacted our lives</summary></entry></feed>