<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-04T17:00:50+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Catwizard Blog</title><subtitle>A place to tell our stories.</subtitle><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name></author><entry><title type="html">A thank you letter to the Jhipster Team</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/04/jhipster-thanks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A thank you letter to the Jhipster Team" /><published>2018-05-04T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-05-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/04/jhipster-thanks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/04/jhipster-thanks.html">&lt;p&gt;We have been working together &lt;em&gt;for 11&lt;/em&gt; years now, we are both originally from Venezuela, we started a software company there (http://www.catwizard.io) after we graduated from Computer Engineering in the University, and started our path as software development as well as entrepreneur. We had a partner those days that recommended Spring as the backend, we developed our first product called Catwizard, a CMS + Product Catalog. It was all growing slowly but surely until Venezuelan economy and personal security levels started a fast decline. There were some common products like toilet paper that began to be scarce, there are a lot of weapons in the streets there, and as a result crime went up and we started to look for a place to go, but we did not want stop working together on our company. Because our product had turned into something to sell to companies, and nobody knew us outside of Venezuela, we started working on custom developments primary to a costumer in the USA that we had build a relationship with. They began to make harder and harder demands, to deliver more difficult with better quality, less time and cheaper, and as a result we had to get better as developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after traveling and living in different countries (Colombia, Peru, Chile) we ended up in Spain, a town close to Barcelona called Lloret de Mar a little more then a year ago (now we are in Girona)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the customers we had stoped ordering and use only the minimal support service we offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, when we settled in Spain, we were forced in a very stressfull situation, basically we had to accept a project that was going to affect a big part of an international company in the USA, but we had very little time, a very limited budget to do it and it required security and reliability to handle everyday operations. In any other circunstantes we would not have agreed to it, but we had no other source of income and zero contacts in Spain. No body knows us, we don’t know how to market ourselves here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, 2 days after agreeing to the project I was feeling like I was already behind and very anxious, and then we remembered that we had tried Jhipster some years back messing around in the Internet. I went and looked at it again and was amazed on everything you had built around the generator. The JDL language, the easy of use of the workflow, the Sonar integration. I felt like Mickey in the Fantasy scene where the Wizard is creating a world. There was a way of updating the entities fields and relationships, exporting the model, the production profile was so well packaged, the ElasticSearch… we included ng-prime and solved specific user interface requirements, and the Angular2 was almost out of Beta. I mean I was so excited at the tech behind it and at all it could do for us. Fast forward some months, and we were delivering the project built in jHipster and it was approved for production, replacing a very old legacy lotus notes workflow, allowing collaboration between the users, monitoring, delivering branded PDF’s , etc… we delivered on time, and we even made a profit thanks to the hours we saved. Another module was approved afterwards and we already delivered it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to that we were able to pay for the migration costs, find a better place to live, get the papers in order (I have European pastport and Cindy the residency), and the USA customers say their solution is used in daily operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Cindy submitted the jhipster workshop to Women Tech Makers Barcelona, it’s the most viewed video of all the talks (I think that because is very practical and in Spanish) and we are connecting with the community. I’m helping out in the next Software Craft Barcelona event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are building a product of our own for the education industry, an ionic mobile app that uses jhipster in the backend. We are still very short in money and in an financially unstable situation basically because we are invisible in the market, I don’t even know how to make ourselves visible, and that’s why we had not connected with you sooner and why we haven’t collaborated more actively (I have only helped once updating the documentation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy says that before the Barcelona talk you asked her to contact you so she could collaborate with tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are offering both of us with any tickets you think we could help with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, thank you for making this amazing platform, it was a fundamental solution for a very stressful time of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name><email>ernesto@catwizard.io</email></author><category term="story" /><summary type="html">How this amazing opensource project impacted our lives</summary></entry></feed>