<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-07T10:13:15+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Catwizard Blog</title><subtitle>A place to tell our stories.</subtitle><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name></author><entry><title type="html">A thank you letter to the Jhipster Team</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/07/jhipster-thanks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A thank you letter to the Jhipster Team" /><published>2018-06-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/07/jhipster-thanks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/07/jhipster-thanks.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you letter to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/juliendubois&quot;&gt;Julien Dubois&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/java_hipster&quot;&gt;Jhipster Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Ernesto Buttó, I’m Co-Funder with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/laslorma&quot;&gt;Cindy Marin&lt;/a&gt; of a small software company (currently 3 people) called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catwizard.io&quot;&gt;catwizard.io&lt;/a&gt;. Cindy recently did a &lt;a href=&quot;http://catwizard.io/workshop.html&quot;&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; in Women Tech Makers Barcelona 2018 about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jhipster.tech/&quot;&gt;JHipster&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This platform has made a huge impact on our lives and the people around us. I wanted to thank the JHipster team for making this platform and I thought that the best way we could do it was telling the story, and to offer the little time we can find to help on some tickets as collaborators or maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been working together for 11 years now, we are both originally from Venezuela, we started a software company there that now days is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catwizard.io&quot;&gt;catwizard.io&lt;/a&gt; (originally Bambu Soluciones).
  After we graduated from Computer Engineering in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucab.edu.ve/&quot;&gt;University&lt;/a&gt;, we started our path as software developers as well as entrepreneurs. In those days we had a partner that recommended Spring as the backend of a platform we commercialized there, we developed our first product called Catwizard, a CMS + Product Catalog using the then popular Adobe Flex as a front end. We had a partner that helped us to get started and closed our first sales&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was all growing slowly but surely as we became incrementally better in the technical and business front until Venezuelan economy and personal security levels started a fast decline. There were some common products like toilet paper, eggs, legumes, milk, etc… that frequently began to be scarce, many people are armed with fire weapons there, and as a result crime went up and we started to look for a place to migrate to, but we did not want stop working together on our company. We set up the whole company to run remotely, but our offer at the moment was a set of modules and services that we sold to companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our sales strategy was based on the trust we built, existing customers that wanted new modules, and a support and service-oriented approach that contributed to our reputation which was slowly spreading by word of mouth. So we basically were most of the time in operations and prospects and customers called and visited us.&lt;br /&gt;
 Venezuelan forced many of our customers to close doors, or to stay operating at the minimum depending on the Industry, size, strategic view of the owners, etc…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody knew us outside of Venezuela, we started working on custom developments and consulting primary to costumers in the USA that we had links with, and we started to strengthen our relationships with a particular customer that we already had a good relationship with. However the primary demand was to create custom solutions, not only them, but every customer we acquired began to raise the bar in terms of delivery time and the features difficulty levels. We also refused to give up on our Venezuelan customers that use our services. As a result, we had to get better as developers among the other fronts that an entrepreneur has to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after traveling and living in different countries (Colombia, Peru, Chile, Italy-Sicily), we ended up in Spain, a town close to Barcelona called Lloret de Mar a little more than a year ago (We are in Girona now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, when we settled in Spain, we were forced into a very stressful situation, basically we had to accept a project that was going to affect a core process of our main customers in the USA + A mobile app that uses Bluetooth to connect to a skateboard, but we had very little time, and a very limited budget to do it. The business software touched many areas. It required security and reliability to handle everyday operations, it integrated with SalesForce, to their products marketing information and to their accounting system for inventory information. In any other circumstances, we would not have agreed to it, but we had no other source of income and zero contacts in Spain. Nobody knew us, and we don’t know how to market ourselves here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-worry-jhipster-is-coming-to-help&quot;&gt;Don’t worry, JHipster is coming to help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, 2 days after agreeing to the project I was feeling like I was already behind and very anxious, and then we remembered that we had tried Jhipster some years back messing around on the Internet. I went and looked at it again and was amazed on everything you had built around the generator. The JDL language, the ease of use of the development workflow, the generated security, and roles! the user’s administration, swagger integration, the monitors, the logging, the profiles, java testing, frontend testing, the sonar integration, performance tests, integration tests… I mean… all the options! Once I got a hold of the workflow using GitHub and all the tools you provide I felt like Mickey in the Fantasy scene where the Wizard is creating a world. Now we were able to learn and apply a lot of technologies and concepts that we simply could not afford in the past. There was a way of updating the entities fields and relationships, exporting the model, the production profile is so well packaged, the ElasticSearch… we included ng-prime and solved specific user interface requirements, and the Angular2 was almost out of Beta. I mean I was so excited at the tech behind it and at all, it could do for us and for our customers. Fast forward some months, and we were delivering the project built in JHipster and it was approved for production, replacing a very old legacy lotus notes workflow, allowing collaboration between the users, monitoring, delivering branded PDF’s, creating tasks on the CRM etc… we delivered on time, and we even made a profit thanks to the hours we saved. Another module was approved afterward and we already delivered it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to that we were able to pay for the migration costs, find a better place to live, get the papers in order (I have a European passport and Cindy the residency), and the USA customers say their solution is used in daily operations. Additionally, we were able to help our partner in Venezuela (Fatima Pestana) to deal with a devastating economic crisis, and we were able to help family leave the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Cindy submitted the jhipster workshop to Women Tech Makers Barcelona, at the time of this writing was the most viewed video of all the talks (I think that because is very practical and in Spanish) and we are connecting with the community. Currently, I’m helping out in the next Software Craft Barcelona 2018 event and became GDG at Girona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jhipster-boosts-learning&quot;&gt;JHipster boosts learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, the learning! The learning because of the quality of the generated code (AAA in sonarqube currently!) and because behind each option there are concepts and well thought out solutions to set of problems. There is a huge benefit of seeing how you apply the concepts in practical code because it’s very easy to get confused in this craft about the best practices. For example, is hard to know if a particular approach is a must because of technical debt, or if it’s something that makes sense in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a small example in the Spring part: the service layer… should I build a service layer for every endpoint or can I get away with calling the repository directly? How do we deal with that kind of thing… ok how does jhipster generates it and why? so we go read your documentation, test it with some cases, and very quickly we come to our own conclusions. Because behind your tools there are philosophies and concepts that support the results, and because you provide several options regarding a particular practice, we can compare and learn faster and better… Oh! yes let’s use service class in this case, interface in that case, but mostly let’s just call the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recomend 100% to anyone who is in the path of learning about Java + Angular/React/Ionic , or about architectures, or about microservices, or about spring security, or about devops (because the profiles, CI tools, deployment and docker stuff is awesome!), or about data modeling, or comparing paradigms like NoSql vs Sql, or about multilanguage architecture, etc… if you want to learn it faster and better, create a simple project with jhipster, see what it does, add a technology you would like to understand, see what it does, repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I was learning and implementing docker, and we have a real use case of a company that has two monolith applications that work together communicating through their JSON API’s. I wasn’t sure if this was right, or common or if there are ways of packaging them. Then in your docker section I found:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If your architecture is composed of several JHipster applications, you can use the specific docker-compose sub-generator, which will generate a global Docker Compose configuration for all selected applications…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ooohh!! So it’s ok, they don’t have to be microservices to connect, and look at the docker-compose files! We can start from here for sure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jhipster-changed-the-game-for-us&quot;&gt;JHipster changed the game for us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, every technology in this solution has a reason to be, it’s useful, and more if it’s combined with another one. But to successfully implement these combinations (JWT Spring security + Angular for example, or ElasticSearch… or Social, etc..) is not trivial. If you want to learn about it you need a lot of time, and budgets of SMBs project won’t cover for these researchers. You, and Deepu and all the core team changed that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, thank you for making this amazing platform, it was a fundamental solution for a very stressful time of our lives and it’s a fundamental part of our learning and as solutions providers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name><email>ernesto@catwizard.io</email></author><category term="story" /><summary type="html">How this amazing opensource project impacted our lives</summary></entry></feed>