<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://blog.catwizard.io/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://blog.catwizard.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-11T08:21:28+01:00</updated><id>http://blog.catwizard.io/</id><title type="html">Catwizard Blog</title><subtitle>A place to tell our stories.</subtitle><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name></author><entry><title type="html">Software Integrations and the sacredness of time</title><link href="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/12/10/integrations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Software Integrations and the sacredness of time" /><published>2018-12-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-12-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/12/10/integrations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/12/10/integrations.html">&lt;div id=&quot;entry-table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc-wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;toc-toggle&quot; class=&quot;no_toc&quot;&gt;
  Table of Contents &lt;i class=&quot;toc-toggle-icon fas fa-chevron-down&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#thank-you-integration-for-relieving-the-pain&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-thank-you-integration-for-relieving-the-pain&quot;&gt;Thank you Integration, for relieving the pain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-sacredness-of-time-your-most-important-resource&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-the-sacredness-of-time-your-most-important-resource&quot;&gt;The sacredness of time, your most important resource&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#capital&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-capital&quot;&gt;Capital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#people&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#time&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-time&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-do-pim-sap-zapier-and-bi-have-in-common&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-do-pim-sap-zapier-and-bi-have-in-common&quot;&gt;What do P.I.M, S.A.P, Zapier and B.I have in common&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#our-first-and-simple-integrations-exp&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-our-first-and-simple-integrations-exp&quot;&gt;Our first and simple Integrations Exp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#market-facts-systems-integrations-an-increasing-focal-point-for-businesses&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-market-facts-systems-integrations-an-increasing-focal-point-for-businesses&quot;&gt;Market Facts: Systems Integrations, an increasing focal point for businesses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-summarized-checklist-for-software-integration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-a-summarized-checklist-for-software-integration&quot;&gt;A Summarized Checklist for Software integration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#finding-the-middle-ground-custom-vs-off-the-shelf-software&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-finding-the-middle-ground-custom-vs-off-the-shelf-software&quot;&gt;Finding the middle ground: Custom vs Off The Shelf Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#jhipster-a-recommended-custom-development-technology&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-jhipster-a-recommended-custom-development-technology&quot;&gt;Jhipster: A Recommended Custom Development Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#thank-you-support-if-you-can&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-thank-you-support-if-you-can&quot;&gt;Thank You, support if you can&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#references&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thank-you-integration-for-relieving-the-pain&quot;&gt;Thank you Integration, for relieving the pain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scotty:&lt;/strong&gt; She’s all yours, sir. All systems automated and ready. A chimpanzee and two trainees could run her!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain Kirk:&lt;/strong&gt; Thank you, Mr. Scott. I’ll try not to take that personally.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— &lt;a href=&quot;http://quotegeek.com/quotes-from-movies/star-trek-iii-the-search-for/6805/&quot;&gt;STAR TREK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I came out of the dentist office. She went for a check-in but they had to operate, she ended up drugged, and disoriented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Make sure she takes this drug in the next hour or so, else the pain will bring her to tears once the sedative wears off, there is a pharmacy right in front of the building, but you know, lately patients have told me the drug is hard to find”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a sunny day in Caracas, Venezuela, and the drug was a common one, but our political and economic situation was starting to be uncommon. We went to the pharmacy, no luck, then to the next one… same luck… none!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time was running out when she grabbed me by the arm while I was driving, and told me… “Use the web page we developed for god’s sake!! It’s starting to hurt!!”… Riiiight, I had forgotten about that one…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/integrations_1/farmaplus_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;farmaplus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-sacredness-of-time-your-most-important-resource&quot;&gt;The sacredness of time, your most important resource&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man is ill-equipped to manage time, however, time is the most important resource in your life, and in your business. Traditionally, business theory teaches us that there are 3 types of resources: Capital, People and Time. Let’s break it down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;capital&quot;&gt;Capital&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Time is also a unique resource. Of the other major resources, money is actually quite plentiful. We long ago should have learned that it is the demand for capital, rather than the supply thereof, which sets the limit to economic growth and activity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Effective-Executive-Definitive-Harperbusiness-Essentials/dp/0060833459&quot;&gt;The Effective Executive&lt;/a&gt;
 by Peter F. Drucker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And regarding people, we can always hire people, even though good people are hard to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;time&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for time, no matter how high the demand, the supply will not go up. There is no price for it, and it can’t be stored in any way. Yesterday time is gone and it will never come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, everything requires time, it is the true and only universal condition. All work takes time, uses time, requires time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… Yet most people take for granted this unique, irreplaceable, and necessary resource. Nothing else, perhaps, distinguishes effective executives as much as their tender loving care of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/time.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the best executives in the world go to great lengths to learn how to save their time, so they can use where it matters most, where it makes a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is, however, a magic artifact that comes in many forms that has repeatly been tested and creates pockets of times, so we can store it, save it, re-use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has evolved throught the centuries, from ancient times, and today it’s precent in many forms. Systmes, rules, automations, information flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But I already have systems in the business” you might say… “in fact we have many. And man, what a complication it is! It’s overwhelming!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But ask your self, are your systems working together ? are they &lt;strong&gt;team&lt;/strong&gt; players or individualists? Are they designed to &lt;strong&gt;collaborate and to create a better system (eco-system)&lt;/strong&gt; for everyone? or are they wasting lots of your time? Do they help you to provide the service expected by today’s standards?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design and successful implementation of integrations create a wealth of time. Just in time information converts into fast service, and less worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A man is rich in proportion to the number of things he can afford to let alone&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;-— HENRY DAVID THOREAU, naturalist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But! Just as a drug, systems can do wonders if prescribed correctly, and wreak havoc if applied incorrectly. Take your time to understand the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing these collaborations is not an easy task, and it’s becoming mandatory for survival, I hope this article saves you time, your most valuable resource, and points you in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we go deeper, I want to give you 2 tips that I hope make a difference for you. If you keep these tips in mind in your process then I can die in peace, my work is done in this world. It’s amazing the impact of these 2 and how few organizations do them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tip 1: Test Before You Implement. Yes, do some mockups, or prototypes. They can be done in Google Slides, Invision, or a piece of paper, and put users to the test. This will save you money and time in a huge way, it will help you estimate much better the scope, the development will be in a fraction of the time, and your end product will be many times better. It can save you years!!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tip 2: Calculate your Return Of Investment: Measure your time wasters before and after. Hey, let’s focus on the objective, time is money and both can be measured. Doing an integration project have Tangible Benefits, such as &lt;em&gt;time reduction in tasks&lt;/em&gt;, and Intangible benefits such as &lt;em&gt;ability to offer improved customer service and support&lt;/em&gt;. Focus on Measuring tangible measures.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Return of investment on correctly implemented system integrations are HUGE, and measuring them is necessary to enable the success of the project, justify future developments, and ensure that your organization gets value for your money. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axia-consulting.co.uk/html/basic_roi_calculation.html&quot;&gt;See this guide for tools and spreadsheets to get you started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Every business is a software business”&lt;/em&gt; said Watts S. Humphrey, the father of quality in software and CMMI 2 decades ago, and it’s &lt;strong&gt;repeated by The CEO of Microsoft, Satya Nadella&lt;/strong&gt; today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Every company is a software company. You have to start thinking and operating as a digital company. It’s no longer just about procuring one solution and deploying one. It’s not about one simple software solution. It’s really you yourself thinking of your own future as a digital company.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-pim-sap-zapier-and-bi-have-in-common&quot;&gt;What do P.I.M, S.A.P, Zapier and B.I have in common&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/integrationBoards.png&quot; alt=&quot;Integration_Boards&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flydata.com/the-6-challenges-of-big-data-integration/&quot;&gt;flydata.com: The-6-challenges-of-big-data-integration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, they are all tools to centralize the data across different systems and creating meaningful views from them. Useful, time-saving, smile givers, decision empowering, wealth builders information in human format. Here are some formal concepts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;BI&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Business Intelligence&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Delivers relative and reliable information at the right people, at the right &lt;strong&gt;time&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;using methods and programs to collect and structure data&lt;/strong&gt;, and presents it in a meaningful and actionable way.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MDM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Master Data Management&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Master Data is the consistent and uniform set of identifiers and extended attributes that &lt;strong&gt;describes the core entities of the enterprise&lt;/strong&gt; including customers, prospects, citizens, supplier, sites, hierarchies and chart of accounts&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;PIM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Product Information Management&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Manages the information required to market and sell products through distribution channels. &lt;strong&gt;A central set of product data&lt;/strong&gt; can be used to feed information to media such as websites, print catalogs, ERP systems, and electronic data feeds to trading partners.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Zapier&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Easy automation for busy people. &lt;em&gt;Zapier moves info between your web apps automatically&lt;/em&gt;, so you can focus on your most important work.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This are a few examples of critical systems, but can you see the common denominator? I see Time and Integration everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining your current systems can achieve more than you can imagine, in most cases more than acquiring new systems. Don’t believe me? ask most legacy banks in the world in what language do they run their core… Does &lt;em&gt;Cobol&lt;/em&gt; rings a bell? well it shouldn’t, Cobol is one old piece of technology, no longer taught in most computer science careers, but a scary size of the financial transactions of the world runs on top of it, &lt;a href=&quot;https://devops.com/cobol-completely-obsolete-omnipresent-language/&quot;&gt;around 80%!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cobol.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cobol Image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://devops.com/cobol-completely-obsolete-omnipresent-language/&quot;&gt;COBOL: Completely Obsolete But Omnipresent Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, combine Cobol with newer tech like mobile apps, and it creates powerful experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-first-and-simple-integrations-exp&quot;&gt;Our first and simple Integrations Exp&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The vision is really about empowering workers, giving them all the information about what’s going on so they can do a lot more than they’ve done in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;—BILL GATES, co-founder of Microsoft, richest man in the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 8 years ago, we were asked to estimate, develop and implement a module to our in-house made web software, an online web catalog system (yes the one at the intro!), so it would integrate with the accounting systems of all the stores and provide one unified view of product information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Farmaplus is a pharmacy, and the motivation behind the online system was to save customers time, by giving them price and availability information based on inventory rotation with a 10 to 15 minutes delay, providing them with better service vs the 24 hours delay of the competition back then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It saved time to customers, to employees, gave useful information to laboratories, helped managers and gave a piece of mind to stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, and while the scarcity of medicines and other products increased, this channel transformed the business making it the priority over the conventional printed catalog, became a sales focus point, helped a lot of people including myself to find their medicine, and was responsible for giving meaning and direction to our team and the evolution of that software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years after we internationalized we kept working on integrations, connecting nationals and internationals companies with all kinds of systems: CRM’s such as Salesforce, commercial websites, quoting systems, Shopify implementations, accounting systems,  warehouses, health clubs, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;market-facts-systems-integrations-an-increasing-focal-point-for-businesses&quot;&gt;Market Facts: Systems Integrations, an increasing focal point for businesses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It is your decisions, and not your conditions, that determine your destiny.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;– Tony Robbins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making the decision at the right time define our reality… But for making a good enough decision, we need key information, at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Where are you going bro?”, I asked my brother some years back as I watched him getting ready to party!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“My company is throwing a party, it’s going to be a sick man!”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Awesome! what are you guys celebrating?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“It appears that after 3 years and millions of dollars, our company finally integrated systems from different departments! Everyone is very excited!”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah… brace yourself, bro, it’s going to get geeky. Market and SKU geeky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pim_forrester.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pim Forrester 2018&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, I did months of market research around product information and integration software. We had created a system over the years that solved many integrations issues. We decided to create a business plan for evaluation and see how far could we take it, thus I talked to a lot of software vendors, following the white rabbit into a deep rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enterworks.com/pim/enterworks-leads-2018-forrester-wave-product-information-management/&quot;&gt;Source: 2018-forrester-wave-product-information-management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some facts I pulled out from the research that might hopefully prompt you to take some kind of action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By 2015, 64% percent of adults in the USA &lt;strong&gt;buy online because the products presented there have more precise information than in stores.&lt;/strong&gt;* &lt;em&gt;- Source: Forrester 2016: Product Information Management Solutions, Q4 2016&lt;/em&gt;. This strategy seems to work, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/topics/2477/online-shopping-behavior/&quot;&gt;statista.com&lt;/a&gt;, retail e-commerce sales worldwide are forecast to nearly double between 2016 and 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiences in the B2C world increase B2B purchases&lt;/strong&gt;, almost 75% say that buying from a web page is more convenient than buying to sales representatives when they buy products or services for work. &lt;em&gt;-Source: PIM Is A Cornerstone Of Your Digital Business Why Customer-Obsessed Firms Need Product Information Management January 18, 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inriver.com/&quot;&gt;InRiver&lt;/a&gt;, one of the leading PIM vendors, claims that they have an &lt;strong&gt;annual growth rate (CAGR) of %70&lt;/strong&gt;. I did check other vendors data, and all of them have grown big time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;87% of data leaders and analysts implemented or are planning to implement or expand on PIM&lt;/strong&gt; (Software Integration for Products). Why? Managing spreadsheet and separated systems is not sustainable. To save time, minimize errors, increase the time to market, and manage constantly changing requirements content for allies, digital business need automated checks &lt;em&gt;- Source: Vendor Landscape: Product Information Management (PIM), Q3 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In 2015, %67 of decision makers related to infrastructure said that develop a complete strategy in the cloud was a high or critical priority. &lt;strong&gt;Additionally %56 projected an increase on investment in cloud services by the end of 2015.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;- Source: The Forrester WaveTM: Master Data Management, Q1 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-summarized-checklist-for-software-integration&quot;&gt;A Summarized Checklist for Software integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, before feeling overwhelmed about the challenge at hand, know this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can reap the benefits of integrations, of becoming “digital” one small step at the time. You do not need to invest in a 3-year project now, just commit to 3 months, do a small integration, enjoy the returns of your investment, and afterward put the next brick.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly but uninterrupted. This is a much faster way to become digital, it creates a habit around development, and habits my friend bring on tangible results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Aim for effectiveness&lt;/strong&gt;. What is the one question that if answered faster would solve many problems at once, for the most people in the company? Identify and focus on that one, do not try to take on 10 unarticulated data problems. You won’t solve them, you will create a 7 head beast that will breathe down your neck every night at bedtime, it will waste money, team effort, and most important, waste tons of Time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being &lt;strong&gt;effective&lt;/strong&gt; is about doing the right things while being &lt;strong&gt;efficient&lt;/strong&gt; is about doing things right. Don’t be efficient about things that don’t matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Learn to keep the door shut, keep out of your mind and out of your world every element that seeks admittance with no definite helpful end in view.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;– George Mathew Adams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, a clear vision of the end goal is the most important part, luckily we can rely more on processes to accomplish this, and less in mindfulness meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in processes and methods, in lists and frameworks. This is a simplified checklist of what I consider a very challenging part in software integration. Creating a clear end goal in mind, and modeling the data from the different systems to meet the goal, are both challenging parts of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the purpose of keeping this post relatively short, I created a separate post to talk about this subject in detail. The following is a quick list to give you an idea if it interests you can find more content and references in &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;PART 2 of this post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design and test a prototype/mockup: Having the end goal clear.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measure before and after: Ensure value for your money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modeling Data: Identify Data Entities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choosing the Architecture: Centralized Vs Virtualized&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify Source Systems: Where is my data?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose The Matching Strategy: How to tie it all together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever we choose to develop a tailored system, or customized an off-the-shelf-solution, these steps are common to both approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-the-middle-ground-custom-vs-off-the-shelf-software&quot;&gt;Finding the middle ground: Custom vs Off The Shelf Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The vision always precedes and itself determines the realization.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;– Lillian Whiting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the previous steps, you need to understand why are you doing the integration, identify what data to use, from which systems, and figure out how to merge them together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend to Re-use what is working, use third-party for specific and tested solutions like CRM or E-commerce, and customize the part of your eco-system that ties everything together, that makes you unique… The integration core, the business core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t want to invest in a year project, with a complete re-write or replace of a system, experience major downtime and potential errors, just to have the same system you had before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Word of caution:&lt;/strong&gt; Vendors are usually interested in selling their software. Most commercial offers from the companies that I talked to for P.I.M software do not include the integration itself to the systems in the company, they redirect you to integrators that they know, who at the end of the day, are going to be the more important role than the systems you are buying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they will not tell you this clearly but at the very end of the selling process. At first is all “yes, yes, do not worry, this is what the package is worth, these are the yearly fees, and with that, your problems will be solved, etc…”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several vendors out there, but last time I checked, very few offered key on hand solutions and the ones that do serve the Enterprise segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jhipster-a-recommended-custom-development-technology&quot;&gt;Jhipster: A Recommended Custom Development Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/logo-jhipster.png&quot; alt=&quot;jhipster logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just set it and forget it!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;—- RON POPEIL, founder of RONCO; responsible for more, than $1 billion in sales of rotisserie chicken roasters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have developed a lot of system integrations, and if I had to choose today what technology to use for your custom solution, I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jhipster.tech/&quot;&gt;Jhipster&lt;/a&gt;. After years of consultancy and tons of custom development, I find this platform the most productive and incredibly robust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main benefit of our experience are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reliable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintainable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flexible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Economic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, a big time saver, with a huge B and humongous I and unmistakable G. BIG time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jhipster generates Spring Code at the back end. &lt;a href=&quot;https://spring.io/&quot;&gt;Spring&lt;/a&gt; is the de-facto standard in Enterprise Java, it has been around for at least 16 years, some define it as the source for modern java. It’s reliable, tested and has a huge community, incredibly active, of enterprise developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the front end, there is all sort of options: Angular, React and I saw a Vue.js plugging at their marketplace recently. There are also mobile hybrid generators for both Angular and React tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jhipster_logos.png&quot; alt=&quot;using jhipster&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jhipster.tech/companies-using-jhipster/&quot;&gt;and many more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of it as a magic weapon, you need enough level to use it, but when used correctly it generates enterprise quality for a fraction of the costs. You can integrate technologies that usually would take weeks to integrate, in moments, allowing smaller companies to enjoy the benefits of enterprise technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers using the framework also increase their level considerably, since the generated code follows certified best practices, and the tool encourages you to generate a lot of code to save time, developers learn by example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Incredible fast code generation with many options depending on your needs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A development profile for fast front and backend development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Production profile ready setup (optimized and tested).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generates ready to use API and documentation for web and mobile apps as you code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generation of automated tests for both backend and frontend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quality code analyzer with sonar cloud, to maintain the project secure and easy to maintain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQL, and no SQL databases options such as Oracle, Mysql, Postgre, MongoDB, Casandra, Couchbase&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows API-First development, code generation, and documentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cache options for enhancing performance such as Ehcache, Hazelcast, Infinispan, Memcached&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enterprise-ready Spring Security, out of the box, with users and roles predefined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Out of the box enterprise search features, such as entity filtering and elastic search.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WebSockets integration for real-time communication&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Option to generate Microservices Architecture code generation for big scalable projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;thank-you-support-if-you-can&quot;&gt;Thank You, support if you can&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope this article was fun and helpful for you. If you want me to keep generating content for you, you can tell me what would you like to help you with and you can help us by donating a small contribution in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/ernesto_and_cindy&quot;&gt;patreon page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/ernesto_and_cindy&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/become_a_patron_button.png&quot; alt=&quot;Become a Patreon for Ernesto and Cindy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;PART 2 of this post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; talks more about the details and challanges of software integration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Effective-Executive-Definitive-Harperbusiness-Essentials/dp/0060833459&quot;&gt;The Effective Executive by Peter F. Drucker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/4-Hour-Workweek-Expanded-Updated-Cutting-Edge-ebook/dp/B002WE46UW/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1544377515&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=4+hour+work+week&quot;&gt;The 4-Hour Workweek by Tim Ferris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://es.slideshare.net/Dataversity/lessons-in-data-modeling-data-modeling-mdm&quot;&gt;Lessons in data modeling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axia-consulting.co.uk/html/basic_roi_calculation.html&quot;&gt;Basic ROI Calculation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://es.slideshare.net/MSM_Software/slideshare-software-dev-4-steps-to-roi-aug14&quot;&gt;4 steps to calculating ROI in Software Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://devops.com/cobol-completely-obsolete-omnipresent-language/&quot;&gt;COBOL: Completely Obsolete But Omnipresent Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insightsquared.com/2013/08/effectiveness-vs-efficiency-whats-the-difference/&quot;&gt;The Difference Between Effectiveness And Efficiency Explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name><email>ernesto@catwizard.io</email></author><category term="PIM / MDM" /><category term="Software Integration" /><category term="software" /><summary type="html">Software Integrations</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A thank you letter to the JHipster Team</title><link href="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/06/09/jhipster-thanks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A thank you letter to the JHipster Team" /><published>2018-06-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/06/09/jhipster-thanks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.catwizard.io/2018/06/09/jhipster-thanks.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you letter to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/juliendubois&quot;&gt;Julien Dubois&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/java_hipster&quot;&gt;JHipster Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Ernesto Buttó, I’m Co-Funder with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/laslorma&quot;&gt;Cindy Marin&lt;/a&gt; of a small software company (currently 3 people) called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catwizard.io&quot;&gt;catwizard.io&lt;/a&gt;. Cindy recently did a &lt;a href=&quot;http://catwizard.io/workshop.html&quot;&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; in Women Tech Makers Barcelona 2018 about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jhipster.tech/&quot;&gt;JHipster&lt;/a&gt;, and I wanted to say a few words about how JHipster has impacted our lives and the people around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comes as a way of thanking the JHipster team for making this platform. I figured that the best way we could do it was telling our story of JHipster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been working together for 11 years now. Cindy and I are both originally from Venezuela. We started a software company there that now days is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catwizard.io&quot;&gt;catwizard.io&lt;/a&gt;  (originally Bambu Soluciones). After getting our degrees in Computer Engineering, we started our professional path as software developers while also starting a company. Being programmers and entrepreneurs. During those early days, we were many, not just Cindy and I. We met our first partner, he had the idea of a building an online product catalog solution for a specific industry and a Content Management System to go with it. He sold us that he could sell it and he would become a supporter and mentor for the startup years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend recomended Spring as the backend, we figured Adobe Flex is the future in the front end… We, young and enthusiastic as we were for anything that sounded fancy and productive, followed. So we coded, we build, we sold. It worked! Kinda…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-about-code-business-and-market&quot;&gt;Learning about Code, Business and Market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was all growing slowly but surely as we became incrementally better in the technical and business front. We were learning how to be a company rather than a team, how to be profitable, how to manage money and time, while at the same learning how to write better code, how to manage ourselves as programmers. We learned to hire and to teach, we gave and took, and in the process, we met the third team member that has been working with us since then Fatima Pestana, data engineer with a taste for CSS and helping customers to achieve their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was like setting up the foundations of a house, sure it was slow, but whatever we were building, it was growing steady and strong. Then Venezuela happened. Economy and personal security levels went in a steep decline. Shortages of basic stuff began (toilet paper, eggs, legumes, milk, etc…) while crime rates went dramatically up. Saddened, we started to think about leaving. What future could we have in these circumstances? Then again: how do you leave behind all that you’ve built for years? How do you leave all your promises to your customers and to yourself? How do you just get on a plane, and… start from scratch? A small decision. To get through a door, to get on a car, to give a final hug, and your habits and definitions and reminders of who you are, in an instant, puff…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our company, however… We did not want stop working together. Our company. It grew into us. It was our dream. It was our vision. It was working, it was giving back. We just couldn’t. And at least about that, of all things, we were able to do something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To run it remotely”, we figured. So we did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, easier being said than done, amirite? Our business, our sole business at the moment was this: a set of modules and services that we sold to companies. Our sales strategy was based on trust that we had built, relying on existing customers that wanted new modules, and a support and service-oriented approach that contributed to our reputation spreading mostly by word of mouth. We basically ran most of the time in operations, while prospects and customers called and visited us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Venezuela kept happening. As the country tumbled, many of our customers were forced to close doors, or to stay operating at minimums depending on the industry, size, strategic view of the owners, with a heavy dose of unrelenting optimism, and faith. Lot’s of faith that it will all turn out for the best. Eventually…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what could we do? We can work remotely, ok, but most (not all) of our clients were closing shop, and nobody outside of Venezuela knew us. We figured that we could work on custom developments and consulting, primarily to costumers in the USA that we already had bonds with. Strengthen our relationships, you know. Improve our delivery times and features compliance, become competitive, while not forgetting about those in Venezuela that still relied upon us and somehow managed to stay afloat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;digital-nomads-vs-giving-up&quot;&gt;Digital Nomads vs Giving Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After living on the road for a few months, while being a consulting company and traveling to several countries (living the remote life, hooray!), including Colombia, Peru, Chile, Sicily, we decided to settle ourselves for a while in warm, sunny Spain, in a small city close to Barcelona called Girona. It was working great! We had challenges but we had freedom, we had stress but also relief. Responsibilities but also a taste of peace of mind, and less loud worries about politics or tragically, toilet paper (and I do mean less loud …family and friends are still there). We had left our home, but we were finally feeling like were building a new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost immediately after taking our first breath in our first Spanish flat, we were thrown into a very stressful situation. We accepted a project that was going to affect a core process of our main customers in the USA while a new opportunity involving a mobile app connecting via Bluetooth to an electric skateboard arose (stoked!).  We had very little time, and a very limited budget to handle it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our client’s business software touched many areas. It required security and reliability to handle everyday operations, it integrated SalesForce to their products marketing information system and to their accounting systems. We loved the project, but the resources and time frames were very short for such a software to be built from sratch. I could feel the risk of finishing the project and beraly being able to pay our bills, and in any other circumstances, we probably would not have agreed to do it, but by this time we have no other source of income and zero contacts in Spain. Nobody knew us, and we didn’t know how to market ourselves here. And on the other side there were the skateboard guys. New client, young guys with a revolutionary product at hand, with lots of promise and potential and interesting technologies… No much money upfront but if the project launched and worked then it would also make sense in the buisiness side… And it seemed so much fun!  We just couldn’t say no to that. What if this became the floating skateboard we are all waiting for? Our future selves would’ve never forgiven us. But no time, no money. What can we do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enter-jhipster&quot;&gt;Enter JHipster&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, 2 days after agreeing to the project with our USA client we were feeling like we were already falling behind. Very anxious and all that. We remembered that we had tried JHipster some years back, while fooling around on the Internet. I went and looked at it again and was amazed on everything the team had built around the generator. The JDL language, the ease of use of the development workflow, the generated security, the roles! The user’s administration, swagger integration, the monitors, the logging, the profiles, java testing, frontend testing, the sonar integration, performance tests, integration tests… I mean… all the options, man! Once I got a hold of the workflow using GitHub and all the tools JHipster provided I felt like Mickey in the Fantasia movie, the Wizard Mickey discovering that he has this magic, that he he owns it, and that he can create universes and life! We were suddenly able to learn and apply a lot of technologies and concepts that we simply could not afford in the past. There was a way of updating the entities fields and relationships, exporting the model. The production profile is so well packaged, the cache options, the database options, do you need realtime with websockets ? ultra fast Elasticsearch engine ? internationalization ? got it choose the languages… we included ng-prime and solved specific user interface requirements (Now days there is a module for that in the marketplace), and the Angular2 was almost out of Beta (They support Angular 5 now and React). I mean I was so excited of all the tech behind it and at all it could do for our customers, all it could do for us! Well… Fast forward some months and we are now delivering the project built in JHipster, approved for production (replacing a very old legacy lotus notes workflow, allowing collaboration between the users, monitoring, delivering branded PDF’s, creating tasks on the CRM etc…) and with a very happy client. We delivered on time and turned a profit thanks to the hours we saved. Even more, some other module, one that was approved after all of this and wasn’t even part of the original scope of the project, we were able to include it before hand. We had anticipated and we delivered! We were skipping through time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jhip1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jhipster Generator Example Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to that we were able to pay for the migration costs, find a better place to live, get our legal papers in order. That first breath of our new flat came again, and this time we managed to fully enjoy it. Ecstatic relief. Good news appeared: our client in the USA told us that their solution was used steadily in daily operations. We became able to help our partner in Venezuela (Fatima Pestana) dealing with the, by now, devastating economic crisis. We were helping family and friends leave the country. Thanks to JHipster we became again to not only be sustainable as a company but also to able to give back. To connect with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy came up with the idea of a JHipster workshop for the Women Tech Makers in Barcelona. It would not only show the many technical benefits of JHipster but it could also be purposed as a tool for empowerment. It turned out to be (at the time of this writing) the most viewed video of all the talks (&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/SoxR30Kkwj4&quot;&gt;you can check it out here&lt;/a&gt;). That same workshop inspired me to help in the next Software Craft Barcelona 2018 event and help Cindy to boost a GDG initiative at Girona. Spreading the word, be it via a workshop, or a long article in a small blog seems like the least we could do to say thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of generated update entity view&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jhip2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Example of generated update entity view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jhipster-boosts-learning&quot;&gt;JHipster boosts learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn you shall want and to learn you shall do! There’s so much to learn from JHipster. I mean… Let’s start with the code. The quality of the generated code (AAA in sonarqube currently!) is the result of well-thought concepts and solutions aimed at a very specific set of problems. What JHipster does, it does it well. Considering how easy it is to get confused in this world about best practices, best methodology, best strategies, best this, best that… There is a huge benefit of seeing those best bests in a tangible product, functioning in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small example in the Spring part: the service layer… Should I build a service layer for every endpoint, or can I get away with calling the repository directly? How should we deal with that kind of thing…? Ok, how does JHipster generates all those abstraction layers and why? Now, as responsible programmers, we go and read the documentation, test it with some cases, and very quickly arrive at our own conclusions. Because behind the tools there are philosophies and concepts that support the results, and because you provide several options regarding a particular practice, we can compare, we can experiment and tinker, we can be playful! (and everybody knows the importance of play)… Oh! yes let’s use service class in this case, interface in that case, but mostly let’s just call the repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example swagger integration, out of the box JSON API interactive interface sandbox!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jhip3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jhipster Generator Example Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can recommend 100% JHipster to anyone who is on the path of learning about Java + Angular/React/Ionic , or about architectures, or about microservices, or about Spring security, or about DevOps (because the profiles, CI tools, deployment and docker stuff is awesome!), or about data modeling, or comparing paradigms like NoSQL vs SQL, or about multilanguage architecture, etc…If you’re reading this and are still not sure, I say: Yes, go through books and online courses and MOOCs and whatnot, but—as it is with anything worthy in this life—, I encourage you to get your hands dirty, as anything worthy in this life requires… Now, if you decided that yes, that you do want to get to the depths of some tech, to see it as it is and understand what it does, how it does it and what it really has to offer, not necessarily become an expert but really knowledgeable… I mean, if you really want to get your hands dirty, why not do it with some really really good mud? This is the algorithm: create a simple project with JHipster, see what it does, add a technology you would like to understand, see what it does now, repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I was learning and implementing docker, and we have a real use case of a company that has two monolith applications that work together communicating through their JSON API’s. I wasn’t sure if this was right, or common or if there are ways of packaging them. Came again JHipster. In the Docker section of the documentation I found this gem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If your architecture is composed of several JHipster applications, you can use &amp;gt; the specific docker-compose sub-generator, which will generate a global Docker &amp;gt; Compose configuration for all selected applications…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ooohh!! So it’s ok! It’s OK. They don’t have to be microservices to connect. And look at the docker-compose files! Certainly, we can start from here…!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jhipster-changed-the-game-for-us&quot;&gt;JHipster changed the game for us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this point, you must know that every technology in JHipster has a reason to be. It is useful by itself, yes, but it can be even more if combined with another one. To successfully implement these combinations (JWT Spring security + Angular for example, or ElasticSearch… or Social, etc..) by yourself is not trivial. Lot’s of trial and error, lot’s of mistakes, maybe even some expensive ones If you want to learn about it you need a lot of time, and budgets of SMBs project won’t cover for these researchers. JHipster provides a way. A low-cost way of learning not how to be a developer but how to be a good one. Not only using Spring in blind-following-the-blind fashion like when we were starting in Venezuela, but using it well; and that along Elasticsearch, and Docker, and Swagger and a myriad of other outstanding packages…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of generated monitor screen&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jhip4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jhipster Generator Monitor Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, JHipster was a fundamental solution during a very hard time of our lives, and it is now a fundamental part of our learning, our processes as developers and our processes as service providers. What else can I say but thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ernesto Butto</name><email>ernesto@catwizard.io</email></author><category term="story" /><summary type="html">How this amazing opensource project impacted our lives</summary></entry></feed>